Jaden Baptista

Professional Summary

Self-motivated and forward-thinking young professional with over a decade of background in software development and full-time experience in at least eight programming languages. Experienced in seizing opportunities to use new technologies and development ideologies while simultaneously creating and maintaining easy-to-use products for multiple employers. Enthusiastic about the JAMstack, but skilled in more traditional applications as well.

Work History

Eco York LLC - Lead Full-Stack Developer

York, PA

05/2019 - Current

- Completely redesigned and redeveloped front-end and back-end of Compass Wave, a estimating tool for residential cleaning service companies
- Designed and developed sophisticated yet easy-to-use additions to the Compass Wave toolset, including but not limited to integrations with Stripe Connect, invoicing, client-side PDF report generation, adding custom questions to the estimation tool, a custom booking form, and an AI-driven smart scheduler
- Learned to work with legacy systems while simultaneously moving the project forward (e.g. creating a custom, minimal component-based client-side framework inspired by React to integrate smoothly with the monolithic PHP backend)

Energy Design Systems, LLC - Lead Full-Stack Developer York, PA

05/2019 - Current

- Collaborated closely with management to efficiently maintain and add onto several legacy products
- Worked with customers directly, maintaining the fastest customer inquiry response time and the highest total of conversations with customers among by coworkers
- Developed a new product from the ground up in Laravel and MySQL
- Became the driving force behind a motivation to embrace serverless technology (AWS Lambda, Netlify, FaunaDB, etc) in planned new versions of their flagship
- Applied knowledge of database normalization in planning out new improvements to their large MySQL database
- · Audited all company users with custom automation scripts several times, picking out and solving many issues with the company's billing system that were created by previous developers and managers

Jaden Baptista Consulting - Owner

Felton, PA

10/2019 - Current

Worked as a freelance web developer on JAMstack-based side-projects such as:

- · Cardamom, an online ecommerce store that highlights and rewards users for growing the platform
- A custom site advertising the services of J & J Auto Programming
- · Milo, a online API-run chat service with a focus on giving customers data about the client's they're speaking to

jaden@baptista.dev (717) 424-0772

Skills

- Project Management
- Product Development
- Back-end and front-end development
- Product Branding
- Algorithm implementation
- Code reviews
- Communication with upper management and customers
- Font design

Languages

- Python, 10+ years
- HTML, JavaScript, and CSS, 8+ years
- SQL, 7+ years
- PHP and XML, 3 years
- Rust and C++, 1 year
- Invented custom interpreted, template-based language called Beryl that reads as plain English

Education

Expected in 12/2020

Harrisburg Area Community College

Harrisburg, PA

Associate of Applied Science: Web Development And Design 4.0 GPA

06/2019

4.0 GPA

Pennsylvania Cyber Charter School Midland, PA High School Diploma

While none of these projects have as of yet been completed, they've given me extensive experience in working with the JAMstack, creating APIs, moving non-proprietary logic to the front-end, and working with customers directly.

Sidus - Product Manager

Midland, PA

10/2018 - 04/2019

- Built a social media app for educational purposes from the ground up in Node.JS, Python, and PostgreSQL
- Led a team of 3-8 developers, designers, and pen-testers in bringing this program to life
- Leveraged technologies such as Heroku, Express, and Flask, as well as established principles of modern web development and design
- Implemented complicated CSS transitions and customizable settings to complement the flexbox-based layout
- Made substantial use of the JAMstack ideology in creating a natural-language artificial intelligence to read conversations when given permission and suggest appropriate educational content from Google, Youtube, netTrekker (knovationlearning.com/school-solutions/nettrekker) and ERIC (eric.ed.gov)
- Worked extensively with WebSockets and creating a polling system
- Pitched Sidus to several potential buyers using deep understanding of the intended audience and its needs
- Employed a competition-based cybersecurity routine designed to patch up potential weak spots before they become a problem